# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 最近我们不是做了一个红烧肉嘛
Didn't we make a red braised pork recently?
# 我说那个红烧肉炖个一两个小时肯定是很耙和
I said that the pork stewed for an hour or two must be pretty soft.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 很软的
very soft
# 然后就有粉丝就给我发私信
And then one of my fans sent me a message...
# 他说买了一坨肉就回家煮了
He said he bought a piece of meat back home.
# 两三个小时咬都咬不动
He couldn't even bite after stewing it for two or three hours.
# 我就跟他说 我说你可能买到了母猪肉
I told him, you probably got a piece of pork from a breeding sow.
# 他不相信
He doesn't believe it.
# 现在我就跟我四伯出来
So now uncle is joining
# 帮我好不容易找了
With tremendous effort,
# 一点老母猪肉
we've found a little bit of pork from a breeding sow,
# 然后找了一块正常的肉
together with another piece of regular pork.
# 这里三块其中一块是正常的
One of the three pieces here is regular pork.
# 今天我请我四伯来给你们普及一下
Today, I've asked my uncle to give you some tips,
# 怎么样来避免买到母猪肉
on how to avoid buying sow pork.
# 这个老母猪肉的边油我给它弄了
I've already cut off the grease side of this pork from old sow.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个皮子母猪肉的皮子
The skin of the sow...
# 有点硬嘎
is harder.
# 绵
tough
# 安
Hmm.
# 很绵
very tough
# 很绵哦
It's very tough.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 显而易见啊
Obviously.
# 我四伯上来就抓了这坨肉
My uncle took this piece of meat as soon as he saw it.
# 这条肉就是母猪肉
This piece of pork is from a sow.
# 母猪肉的话
If it's from a sow,
# 大家可以看到这这个肉特别的长
as you can see, this meat is extremely long.
# 而且很厚
And it's very thick.
# 这个猪有好重哦 四伯爷
How heavy is the pig, uncle?
# 这个肉啊 这个老母猪有六百来斤
This old sow should weigh over 600 jin (300kg).
# 600多斤
Over 600 jin!
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 你看嘛 这些粉丝问买肉 买母猪肉
Look, the fans is asking about pork from a sow.
# 先就喊他看背面
Just ask him to look at the back first.
# 这个奶子 这个奶子很小很平顺
This nipple. This nipple is small and smooth.
# 啊
Hmm
# 它就不是老母猪肉
It's not an old breeding sow.
# 老母猪肉你看这个奶子好长
Look at these long nipples... It must be a sow.
# 小猪儿吸
Piggies sucked them.
# 这就是小猪儿吸过的这种老母猪
This is the kind of nipples that the little piggies sucked.
# 然后这边安
And then here...
# 等一哈都四伯爷
Wait a minute, Uncle
# 这里我想提个问
I'd like to ask a question here.
# 啊
Hmm?
# 那人家把那个猪皮下了的安
If the butcher cuts the skin out of the pork...
# 下了然后你就对着这个奶子喊他割了给你看
you should then ask him to cut the nipple and show you inside.
# 割一刀给你看
I'll cut it for you.
# 看到有这种奶砂（乳腺）
You can see the "milk sand" (mammary gland).
# 你看这个奶砂（乳腺）跟这个这个白肉不一样
Look at the difference between this milk sand (mammary gland) and this white meat (fat).
# 看到没
You see?
# 大家可以看一下这里
You can take a look here.
# 这里有那个深红色的这个
Here's the crimson one.
# 奶砂（乳腺）
Milk sand (mammary gland)
# 奶砂(乳腺）啊叫
Milk sand (mammary gland)?
# 嗯 叫奶砂（乳腺）
Yeah. Milk sand.
# 然后这边看看
And then look over here.
# 这边就是正常的肉的颜色
This is the normal color of pork.
# 划一刀看哈看四伯爷
Cut it to have a look, Uncle.
# 拿刀来划一哈嘛
Use that knife.
# 划给大家看一哈看
show you guys all.
# 看个奶砂跟这个肉就不一样
Look at the difference between the milk sand and this meat.
# 跟这个边子肉就不一样
It's not the same.
# 大家对比一下 你看
Let's compare. Look.
# 这个就是乳汁要从这里经过
This is where the milk passes through.
# 所以它跟那个脂肪 它是分明的
So it's not same as the fat. It's distinct.
# 这块的肉到底是瘦的还是肥的哦
Is this piece of meat (milk sand) lean or fat?
# 奶砂呀它又不是瘦的也不是 就是肥的变了质的
milk sand...it's not lean, it's like kind of fat but it's not good...
# 皮子没剐 就认这个奶嘴这儿就认出来了
If the butcher didn't cut off the skin, the nipples here are more recognizable.
# 然后它皮子剐了又咋子认安
And then what happens when they cut its skin off together with the fat?
# 啊
Hmm...
# 就认这个肉 这个肉带黑色
You need to look at this meat. It's blackish.
# 这个就是说这个颜色比较深
I mean, it's darker.
# 然后大家可以看下这这一块
You can have a look at this piece.
# 这个平猪的你看
Look at this regular pork.
# 这一块是阉割过得小公猪
This one is from a baby castrated male pig.
# 从小就是阉割了的 就是为了吃它的肉
It was castrated when it was little, a standard procedure for meat pork.
# 然后大家看看这个颜色
And then you can see the difference in color.
# 这个是粉红色
This one's pink.
# 这个有点带褐色有点深褐色
This one's a little brownish, darker brown.
# 然后大家可以看下正常的肉只有这么厚
Then you can see that regular pork is only this thick.
# 一般来说我们这个商品猪只会养到200斤左右
Generally speaking, commercial meat pigs are only raised to about 200 Jin.
# 200斤左右
About 100 kg.
# 200多斤 两百四五十斤 大不了就是300斤左右
200 Jin, 240 or 250 Jin, or 300 Jin maximum.
# 如果说故意把它喂到六七百斤的猪很少
It's rare to to raise it up to 600 or even 700 Jin
# 然后就是这个猪脚
And then there's this pig's leg.
# 这个猪脚也是我们找了很久才找到的母猪肉
This foot is also from a breeding sow. We had a hard time finding it.
# 你看那坨肉好黑哦
Look how dark that meat is.
# 这两块肉不是出自同一个猪身上
These two pieces of meat are not from the same pig.
# 但是它的颜色是一样的
But they got the same color.
# 这个是老母猪
This is a very old sow.
# 这个母猪没有不是特别老
This sow isn't that particularly old.
# 但是颜色基本上相当
But the colors are basically the same.
# 还有就是这个皮老母猪的皮比较粗糙
And the skin of old sow is rougher.
# 摸着扎手的
It's thorny,
# 扎手的哈
and may prick your hand
# 然后它的瘦肉啊
Then the lean meat...
# 这个肉部分非常的老
is very tough.
# 这个油熬起就要起珠珠
The oil will be pearly when it's boiled,
# 起珠珠
like pearl beads.
# 那个油就要起绿豆大小的珠珠
That oil is going to be as big as green beads.
# 哦
Oh.
# 平猪（商品猪）熬起就没得
Commercial meat pigs don't have that when boiled.
# 平猪熬起就是一块板 你就看不出
The lard oil will be a slab when you use a regular meat pig.
# 我四伯的意思就是这个油
I will explain a bit more what my uncle meant.
# 如果是熬猪油它出来有绿豆那么大的油珠
If you render lard with it, and beads in the size of green beans can be seen,
# 就是会散花发感觉很漂亮的那种
You know, is like fat bead, which looks nice,
# 这个是母猪的特性
it means that it is from a breeding sow.
# 所以我们对比一下
So let's compare.
# 母猪大家可以看母猪
Sows. Everyone can notice...
# 最直观的就是看到的乳头够长
The most obvious is that the nipples are long.
# 因为小母猪 这个因为小猪吸过很长
Because they have been sucked by the piglets for a long time.
# 然后如果是去掉皮的话大家看这中间
And then if the skin is removed, you can see the middle layer here.
# 它这个脂肪层
The fat layer.
# 这个奶砂
The milk sand.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 脂肪层不正常颜色很深很密
The fat layer is abnormally dark and dense.
# 然后第三个的话就是看颜色
And then third, is the color.
# 颜色这个瘦肉的颜色更深
This lean meat is darker.
# 第四个就是口感老母猪的那个肉啊
The fourth is the texture of the sow's meat.
# 煮个两三个小时都咬不动
It takes two or three hours to cook, but it's extremely chewy.
# 还有就是最重要的一点对比下价格
And another important point is to compare prices.
# 这个现在这个时候就要卖二十七八
This one's going for 27 or 28 yuan at this time.
# 二十七八
27 or 28
# 啊
right
# 那这个安
And this one?
# 这个我今天去给你买的七块五
I bought this one today, and it was only 7.50 yuan.
# 我四伯去给我到处打听 去找的
My uncle was asking around for it.
# 找来七块5一斤
And it was only 7.50 yuan per Jin.
# 这个价格差不多相差了四倍
That's almost a four times difference in price.
# 相差了4倍这个价格
That's four times the price.
# 但是有很多人 很多摊贩
But there are some butchers, some of the vendors.
# 他不是特别有良心把这个皮下了
who might, out of bad intention, take the skin off,
# 拿来当普通的猪肉来卖
and sell it as ordinary meat pork.
# 噶
right?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个应该是不怎么厚道的
This should consider as immoral.
# 还有就是人家说
And somebody say
# 就是老人家都说母猪肉孕妇吃了要咋子安
I mean some old folks say that pregnant women should definitely avoid eating sow meat?
# 孕妇吃了 以后小孩子就要得母猪疯
If a pregnant woman eats it, her baby will get "sow madness"
# 割都割不动这个肉筋
I can't even cut the tendon.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 其实这个还是有一定的科学依据的
Actually, there is some scientific evidence for this...
# 孕妇最好还是不要去吃刚下完崽的母猪
Pregnant women are better off not eating sows that have just given birth.
# 对身体不是特别好
It's not particularly good for health.
# 还有就是大家买这个肉啊
And those who buy pork,
# 一定要分清楚以后不要再上当受骗了
Be sensitive and don't be fooled again!
# 就是可能买来炖几个小时都炖不耙的
You might buy it and stew it for hours, but still can't soften it.
# 那绝对是有问题 是猪有问题
There's definitely something wrong. Something wrong with the pig.
# 说母猪公猪要说买骨头买排骨的哈
If we buy ribs, how can we identify the breeding sow and the breeding boar?
# 就喊这些人些
Just ask the butcher...
# 把手去摸肚皮里面的排骨
Let you feel the ribs on the inside of the belly.
# 拿手给它一摸
Feel it by hands.
# 没得油的 是光滑的就是公猪和母猪的排骨
If there's no oil. It's smooth. It's boar and sow ribs.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 就是说那个公猪那个排骨 手一摸不沾油
I mean, if the ribs do not give a greasy touch at all,
# 就可能有问题
there might be a problem.
# 是这个意思噶
That's what it means.
# 嗯对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
# 母猪还不是一样的啊 是一个性质
A sow is the same. It's the same thing.
# 那个公猪
And breeding boars...
# 这个老母猪你拿到这样子一闻 你还闻不到腥臭
if you smell this old sow, you can't smell the stink.
# 但是那个公猪你拿来闻
But you can smell it from a breeding boar.
# 啊
Hmm
# 马上现场直播你就闻到是腥臭的
You'll smell something bad and stinky right away.
# 是因为这个猪啊
It's because of the pig...
# 没有经过阉割它的性器官发育很成熟
The sex organs are fully developed without castration.
# 因为它是种猪嘛 要为了给母猪配崽
Because it's a breeding pig. It's for making new piglets.
# 所以它这个性器官一旦发育成熟之后会有一股
If the sexual organ matured, it smells like...
# 特别的一种骚味 是这个意思啊
It's a special kind of smell. That's what it means.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 好 我今天来总结一下
Okay, I'll make the conclusion.
# 第一个是这个老母猪肉炖不耙 咬不动
The first is that the old sow's meat is forever chewy.
# 这个价格跟普通的商品猪肉价格相差了差不多4倍
The price is basically just a quarter of regular commercial pork.
# 这个还是有一点
That's a bit...
# 有点这个怎么说呢
It's a little... how should I put this?
# 还是有点不是很厚道噶
It's not very kind to sell breeding pigs as if they were regular.
# 嗯 确实
Yeah, indeed.
# 如果要卖的话一定要告诉大家
If you're going to sell it, make sure you tell everyone.
# 这个就是母猪肉你们要买的话可以买
It's a sow. Buy it if you want it.
# 嘎 这个做人要诚信
Honesty is everything.
# 好吧视频就到这里
All right, that's it for the video.
# 如果你们还有什么不懂的发私信再来讨论一下
If there's anything else you don't understand, leave me comments and we'll discuss it.
# 或者说全国各地粉丝朋友们你们也讲一下
Or fans and friends from all over the country, tell us more about it.
# 就是我们上一代人关于说这个
We can discuss what our last generation said about breeding pigs,
# 人吃了母猪肉会怎么样讨论一下
about what happens when people eat the pork from a sow.
# 还有就是这个肉我们自己是不会吃的
And we're not going to eat this meat ourselves.
# 就我们不是有小黄（狗)吗
Don't we have our little yellow (the dog)?
# 漆二娃
Qi Erwa
# 等会把这个肉宰成小坨坨 弄来煮熟 煮熟来喂它
Go to cook this meat, and feed it to him.
# 拿给它吃哈
Feed him, Ha!
# 拿来喂狗
Feed it to the dog.
# 啊
right
# 我估计这儿都要够它吃好久 这坨我们自己吃
I'm guessing there's enough here to feed him for a long time. We'll eat this one ourselves.
# 那坨炖起肯定只有我们自己吃哦
We'll be the only ones to eat that...
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里了 拜拜
All right, that's it for this video. Bye.